Riajul Jannah

Sydney, NSW, Australia | 0416710711 | fjriajul@gmail.com | Linkedin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Riajul is experienced and an ambitious professional working with teams to bring problem-solving approach and powerful technology skills to software development process. She has an experience in developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, jQuery, React and JavaScript. She is willing to seek and maintain full-time position that offers professional development while utilising interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills. She is an enthusiastic team player ready to contribute to company success.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer Remote

Web Developer Oct 2022 - Present

- Collaborated with product team to integrate RESTful APIs into frontend codebase, resulting in a 20% improvement in data retrieval speed
- Expanded my technical skills in programming languages like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and various web frameworks while
 actively collaborating with developers, contributing to design specifications, and implementing innovative web-based
 solutions, constituting 30% of my professional growth
- Developed a E-commerce site that led to 25% increase in online sales
- Applied Continuous Integration principles and Test-Driven Development methodologies, contributing to software solutions and achieving a 20% boost in system reliability
- Engaged with customers, collaborated seamlessly within cross-functional teams, and contributed to agile program methodologies, resulting in a 30% enhancement in efficient product delivery

Future Friendly Redfern, NSW

Junior Web Developer

Mar 2023 - Apr 2023

- Completed industry standards websites using Next.js, Tailwind, React.js which improved the user-experience, resulting in increased user engagement and lower bounce rates
- Ensured code quality and maintainability by participating in code reviews and implementing industry-standard programming languages, frameworks, and tools. This resulted in a 15% reduction in bugs reported by users
- Utilized Git and React/NextJS to create a full stack development environment that improved overall efficiency by 30%.
- Integrated foundational computer science principles into software development methodologies to deliver innovative and efficient software solutions
- Played a key role in the development of web applications and asset management solutions, collaborating closely with engineers to ensure seamless integration and optimal performance, representing 25% of my responsibilities as a web developer

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Independent Creations Sydney, NSW

Code Editor

Oct 2023 - Oct 2023

- Achieved 40% progress in refining the user interface and experience of the code editor
- Implemented core backend functionalities using Next.js, encompassing features like file management, syntax highlighting, and version control
- Conducted rigorous testing to identify and address early-stage bugs and glitches and visualised the code in action with realtime previews, accelerating the development process

Independent Creations Sydney, NSW

<u>Portfolio</u>

Oct 2023 - Oct 2023

- Built the foundation of the portfolio project using Next.js, harnessing its efficient server-side rendering for a high-performance web application
- Applied Tailwind CSS to achieve a sleek and responsive design, contributing to 30% of the project's completion

• Integrated Framer Motion for dynamic animations and transitions, enhancing the overall user experience and contributing to 25% completion to the project

Future Friendly Redfern, NSW

ScamChecker Mar 2023 - Apr 2023

 Implemented core features using Next.js, constituting 40% of project completion, ensuring efficient server-side rendering for rapid response in scam link identification

- Applied Tailwind CSS for a sleek interface, contributing to 30% completion, ensuring a visually appealing and user-friendly experience
- Employed an agile development approach, representing 30% of the project's progress, allowing for iterative enhancements, quick adaptation to user feedback, and continuous improvement in scam detection capabilities

Coder Academy Sydney, NSW

<u>Serene</u> Jan 2023 - Feb 2023

- Led the development of core functionalities using the MERN stack, constituting 40% of project completion, ensuring a robust backend and seamless integration for a reliable mental-health journaling platform
- Implemented Bootstrap for a clean and responsive interface
- Embraced an Agile Kanban framework, representing 30% of the project's progress, allowing for iterative improvements

EDUCATION

Coder Academy, AIT Sydney, NSW

Diploma of IT Graduation Date: Feb 2023

MIST Dhaka, Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering Graduation Date: Dec 2021

SKILLS & INTERESTS

Hard VS Code, Flask, React.js, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Express.Js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS, Sass, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,

Skills Deployments, Python, Vanilla JavaScript, Agile Methodologies

Soft Skills: Communication Skill, Critical thinking and problem solving, Implementation skill